Instructor: Hello my friends,
welcome to this new tutorial.
In this one I'm gonna show you
how to install R and RStudio on your machine.
All right, so let's do this.
We have to start with R.
So, here in the search bar we're gonna type C-R-A-N,
press enter, and we're gonna click the first link
of the Comprehensive R Archive Network,
because that's exactly where we can download and install R
for the three systems: Linux, macOS, and Windows.
So, let me show you quickly how to do it for the three,
starting with Linux. Download R for Linux.
So here, make sure to choose your Linux system.
For example, I'm gonna show this to you for Ubuntu,
and then you simply need to follow the instructions here.
So, you open your Linux terminal,
then you're gonna enter these four command lines,
after which you will run this command line
to install R and its dependencies, and that's it.
That's all you need to do on Linux.
You just install R by running these commands.
All right, so now let me show you
how to do this for Windows.
For Windows, I recommend to click "base" here
because this is the easy option
if you want to install R for the first time.
So, let's do this. Let's choose this one.
And then you simply click this link
to install the latest R version.
You might get a different one when you take this tutorial.
At the time I'm speaking it is 4.2.2, all right?
I'm on a Mac, so I'm not gonna download here,
and well, speaking of Mac,
I'm gonna show you now how to download R for macOS.
So, we click this link here,
then we're gonna take the latest release again,
and then make sure here to select the right PKG file
according to your macOS system.
So, for macOS 11 Big Sur and higher,
Apple silicon arm64, this is what you want,
and then for macOS 10.13 High Sierra and higher,
Intel 64-bit, this is what you want.
So, as far as I'm concerned, I'm in this case,
and so I'm gonna click this link
to download the version 4.2.2 of R,
and so I'm gonna click "save," and this will download R.
There we go, it was very fast.
So, now I'm gonna go to my Downloads folder,
I'm gonna double click it,
and then we're just gonna click "continue" here
to install R on our machine.
Agree and install. There we go.
And now it is installing R, and perfect.
Installation was successful. Great.
So, now you have R on your machine.
That's great, but we want an easy interface,
you know, a very user friendly interface when coding with R
and that's why it's also very good to install RStudio.
So, we're gonna go back to our favorite browser
and this time we're gonna enter RStudio. There we go.
RStudio, you click the first link
and you're gonna download RStudio,
so let's click this link first.
There we go, the RStudio ID, that's exactly what we want,
and we're gonna take the RStudio desktop.
So, let's click "Download RStudio" again,
and let's scroll down and let's find
the right one for our system.
So, download and install R,
We've already done it on CRAN,
and if you scroll down you will find RStudio
for your system.
Alright, Windows, macOS, Ubuntu, Ubuntu 22,
and some more below.
Okay, so here I'm on a Mac,
so again, I'm gonna take this one then save.
Done. So, now I'm gonna go back to my download folder,
I'm gonna double click this one now,
I'm gonna put it in my applications,
and in a second I will have RStudio installed on my machine.
So, let's close this, and now let's open RStudio
and let me introduce you to it.
So, I'm gonna find it right here.
Open and welcome to RStudio.
All right, so first we can see
that RStudio is divided into three panels.
This panel here, which is the console
where you can execute some code,
like for example, two plus two and press "Enter."
Then, this is the environment panel
where the variables of your code will be created
when you execute it,
and then the third panel here, which is your files,
you know, from your computer,
where you can access your codes and your data set.
So, for example, let's go to my desktop
where I have the whole Machine Learning A to Z
Codes and Datasets folder, and let's enter it.
Let's take, for example, Part 2 - Regression
and the simplest model, Simple Linear Regression,
and then the R folder.
So, here you can find the code
of the Simple Linear Regression model, the R code, right?
And then the dataset Salary_Data.csv.
So, to open the model, you simply click on it.
It will appear here in a fourth panel
where you can edit the code in this R file, right?
So now, just for fun,
just to give us an exciting introductory note on R,
let's execute this code, but before we execute it,
the first thing we always have to do
is to set this folder as working directory folder
so that when we import the data set here
while the console knows where to access it,
which is in this folder,
and so to set this folder as working directory,
we simply click "More" here
and then set as working directory.
There we go, and now we can simply
select the whole code here and then press Command
or Control+Enter to execute it, and there we go.
As you can see now, the code is executing in the console
and soon enough we can see our variables in the environment,
all the variables that are in this code,
and the two plots of the training set and the test set.
Of course, all these steps will be explained in details
when we implement the Simple Linear Regression model.
This was just a teaser of what we're gonna do in R,
and speaking of which,
I'll look forward to seeing you
in the next Practical Activities on Python and R
to implement R models,
and until then, enjoy machine learning.